CHAE LIN KIM

7, Cheongpa-ro 47na-gil, Yongsan-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea (+82)10-4917-4468, ccaa9697@sookmyung.ac.kr, ccaa9697@gmail.com https://chaelin0722.github.io

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a computer science researcher with a focus on deep learning in facial expression recognition with few-shot learning. I have extensive experience in deep learning and AI research with institutions in both Korea and USA, my research is published in multiple international journals and I have presented my research in various conferences.

I am a hardworking and ambitious individual, I am a self-starter and I am highly motivated with a great passion in the field of machine learning.

EDUCATION

Sookmyung Women's University

Seoul, Korea

Master of Engineering in IT Engineering

Sep. 2021 – Aug. 2023 (expected)

• Advisor: Professor Byung-Gyu Kim

Sookmyung Women's University

Seoul, Korea

Bachelor of Engineering in IT Engineering(Magna Cum Laude)

Mar. 2016 – Aug. 2021

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

The University of Akron

Ohio, US

Exchange Research Intern

July. 2022 – Aug. 2022

· Apply deep learning algorithms to Facial expression recognition and electrocardiogram classification

Sookmyung Women's University

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Graduate Researcher

Sep. 2021 – Present

- Conducted surveys for facial expression recognition and meta-learning with a focus on few-shot learning
- · Applied few-shot learning on FER task to solve the overfitting problem of facial expression datasets
- Developed a deep learning-based vision inspection system for a bamboo toothbrush
- Proposed a deep learning-based fault detection algorithm by separating the detection and classification module for manufacturing automation
- Developed matching technology based on context information analysis for expanding the market of online publications
- Currently in process of conducting more research in a wide variety of topics

Sookmyung Women's University

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Intern

Mar. 2021 – Aug. 2021

- Researched identifying valuable features of context information to inference similar types of publications
- Proposed a fusion algorithm of object detection and depth information for detecting dangerous situations in real-time
- Conducted surveys for recent classification and detection of state-of-the-art models and implemented architectures

JOURNAL PUBLICATION

International Journal

1. To be published

Korean Journal

- 1. A Study of the Fault Detection Technique for the Bamboo Toothbrush Manufacturing Automation, Chae Lin Kim(First), Young-Ju Choi, Byung-Gyu Kim*, Eun-Ha Park, Kyung-Tae Lee, KMMS Autumn Conference (KMMS)
- 2. Development of Real-time Dangerous Situation Detection Algorithm Based on Object Detection and Depth Information Fusion, **Chae Lin Kim(First)**, Jeong-Been Seo, Byung-Gyu Kim*, KMMS Spring Conference (KMMS)

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

Korea Multimedia Society (KMMS) Autumn Conference 2021

Nov. 26, 2021

* Online, Republic of Korea • Title: A Study of the Fault Detection Technique for the Bamboo Toothbrush Manufacturing Automation

Korea Multimedia Society (KMMS) Spring Conference 2021

April. 30, 2021

Poster presentation

Online, Republic of Korea

 Title: Development of Real-time Dangerous Situation Detection Algorithm Based on Object Detection and Depth Information Fusion

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Sookmyung Women's University | *Teaching Assistant*

Seoul, Republic of Korea March. 2022 – June. 2022

Image Processing and its Applications

- · Assist and teach MFC window programming with C language using Usual Studio
- Answered questions in person and online, marked assignments, and proctored exams for 30+ students

HONORS AND AWARDS

Graduation with honors: magna cum laude, Sookmyung Women's University	2021
Best honors Award, Sookmyung Women's University	2021
High honors Award, Sookmyung Women's University	2017, 2020
1st Place Award, Java Hackerthon in Jeju CCEI	2019
2nd place Award, Appjam in SOPT	2020
Undergraduate Research Scholarship, Sookmyung Women's University	2021

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

Java Programming Education in Jeju CCEI

Jeju Island, Korea

Member of program

July. 2019 – Aug. 2019

• Designed a location based game application to solve social problems in Jeju island

(SMWU-KSU Interdisciplinary) Hackathon with AWS Educate

Seoul, Korea

Member of program

Feb. 2020

• Proposed deep learning-based app service using text and vibration to alert dangerous situation for auditory disordered people

University student programming union club (SOPT)

Seoul, Korea

Server Engineer

Sep. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Designed an application service of vintage shopping mall as a server engineer and managed database

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Graduate Student Council

Seoul, Korea

Student President

March. 2022 - March. 2023

· Hosted meetings and conferences for professors and graduate students

Sookmyung Unesco-Unitwin ICT education program

Phnom Penh, Cambodia

Student Assistant, Volunteer

Aug. 2020

· Assisted Arduino and mobile application programming course and managed student's hackerthon project

Sookmyung University Major Mentor Program (SUMM)

Seoul, Korea

IT Engineering Mentor

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2021

• Delivered an introduction of IT Engineering lecture once a month and mentored high school students hoping to major in IT Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python (TensorFlow, Pytorch), C/C++, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Developer Tools: Git, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, Visual Studio, Eclipse

Database: MySQL

REFERENCES

Byung-Gyu Kim, Full Professor

Department of IT Engineering Sookmyung Women's University +82-2-0000-0000, bg.kim@ivpl.sookmyung.ac.kr

Gyung-SOO Hong???, IT Solution Architect

NVIDIA

+82-2-0000-0000, tmp@sookmyung.ac.kr